# **Enrique (Eddie) Villarreal**

3830 E. Evans Rd. : San Antonio, TX 78259 : (210) 900-9112

#### **Summary of Qualifications**

Skilled operations manager and highly effective leader with proven history of exceeding project, budgetary and productivity goals. Novice web developer with experience developing web-based, client-side applications. Proficient in JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, Bootstrap and several over frameworks. Always hungry to learn new technologies.

#### Experience

### **General Manager**

#### Centro Med /Centro Fitness, February 2010 to Present

- Manage day-to-day operations of the entire Fitness, Wellness and Events Centers.
- Supervise entire staff including Personal Training, Sales, Reception, Daycare, Housekeeping, and Maintenance teams.
- Interview and select prospective team members for all departments.
- Administer payroll and ordering for all departments while meeting budgetary goals.
- Implemented new practices in account collections that resulted in a 40% decrease in unpaid membership fees.
- Supervise all aspects of facilities management.
- Manage all customer service-related issues.
- Meet all sales targets and prepare upcoming sales budgets.
- Manage relationships with all members/customers and facilitate communication to ensure an outstanding customer experience.
- Motivate team members and ensure continued high employee morale.
- Lead the planning and execution of a new high-profile city-wide weight loss challenge event, with a continued increased in event participation by over the last 6 years.

#### **Operations Manager**

## Spectrum Health Clubs, Medical Center, May 2009 to February 2010

- Supervised facility planning, design, hiring and grand opening
- Served as chief manager for entire health club, including supervising staff of 45 employees.
- Managed reception, housekeeping, sales and facilities departments, as well as scheduling and payroll.
- Responsible for inventory and ordering of all supplies for the club, including gym, locker rooms, aquatic center and tennis facility.
- Handled member affairs, customer service and sales initiatives.

• Planned and executed major club events and fundraisers.

#### **Member and Facilities Supervisor**

### Spectrum Health Club, Rogers Ranch, August 2005 to May 2009

- Worked manager on duty shifts, managing the entire club and all employees, and handling all major issues and situations.
- Processed and documented all daily revenue for the club on the company spreadsheets.
- Supervised entire reception staff, including employee scheduling and payroll.
- Managed all club events including vendor fairs and member appreciation parties.
- Responsible for handling all member affairs, including complaints.

#### Education

# University of Texas at San Antonio August 2001 to May 2006

• BBA in Information Systems

# University of Texas at San Antonio School of Data July 2020 – present

- Enrolled in a 6-month, Full Stack Development Program
- Completion Date is January 2020

#### **Other Skills**

- Fluent in Spanish
- Proficient with Github repositories
- Proficient in HTML, CSS, javascript, Jquery, Bootstrap
- Expert Level MS Office Skills
- Expert Level Adobe Software, ADP, WebEx, Cisco Systems, Social Media, and Club Management Software
- Experienced Public Speaker / Trainer